# **Julio Placeres**

jplaceresvaldes@outlook.com | (315) 878-4223 | Orlando Florida

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/julio-placeres-731280a7/

GitHub: https://github.com/julioPlaceres

Portfolio: https://julioplaceres.github.io/ReactPortfolio/

Looking forward to earning the position of Software Engineer at a leading organization to showcase my skills in programming to generate high-end solutions to general software issues along with a better user experience.

#### **Technical Skills**

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap, WPF, Labview

Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, Handlebars, AWS, Webpack, C#, Labview

# **Projects**

Project Name: Tasty Bytes |

Repo: https://github.com/julioPlaceres/TastyBytes |

Deployed Yes | Backend developer

- **Purpose:** Provides users with recipes based on ingredients they choose from. After inputting the ingredients, a list of recipes will be presented to choose from. Upon selecting a recipe, a summary of cooking instructions, and a food label will be presented. A nice app to have for professionals who might not have the time to plan their meals.
- Tools/Languages: Progressive Web App (PWA), HTML/CSS, Javascript, Bulma CSS Framework, APIs (Spoonacular / The cocktail DB)

Project Name: Budget Tracker |

Repo: https://github.com/julioPlaceres/Budget\_Tracker |

Deployed Yes I

Front and Backend Developer

- **Purpose:** Giving users a fast and easy way to track their money is important, but allowing them to access that information anytime is even more important. Having offline functionality is paramount to our applications success.
- Tools/Languages: Webpack, Minification, Progressive Web App (PWA), HTML/CSS, Javascript, Heroku,
  Service Workers

## **Work Experience**

### Hill Dermaceuticals Inc.

November 2021 - Present

Quality Engineer

Sandford, Florida

- Contributing to develop company's ERP system by expanding and improving the current functionality, fixing bugs and participate in code reviews.
- Validate new computer systems as well as re-validate current systems.
- Provide IT support where needed.
- Back up periodically all systems within the company.

### **ICM Controls**

January 2017 - September 2021

Software Engineer

Syracuse, New York

- Developed SPC Suite that contributed to reducing the number of defects. Dashboards were placed around the company in order to monitor and track production overall performance.
- Developed an application to track the current of components by using Labview displaying the information live to the reliability engineers.
- Provided Support by expanding the ERP functionality, by creating a module for signing in and out products in the warehouse, which saved employer time, and reduced data entry defects.
- Developed an application for auditing, which allowed auditors and management to act accordingly in a timely manner to arising issues.

**ICM Controls** 

November 2013 - December 2017

Quality Auditor & Metrologist

Syracuse, New York

Grad: September 2021

- Created and maintained CNC programs, performing FPI for a variety of components and processes.
- Performed Finish good products audits and Line audits to ensure product quality and enforce standards operating procedures and safety.
- Contributed to achieve and maintain ISO 9001:2008, ISO 9001:2015 as well as ISO14001 as one of the lead auditors.

#### **Education**

University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida Full-Stack web development

Hermanos Gomez, Havana, Cuba Grad: June 2012

Bachelor Degree: Process Control